him to take care of his health, but Boxer paid no attention.
His 12th birthday was approaching. He did not care what happened, so long as a
good store of stone was accumulated before he went on pension.
Late one evening in the summer, a sudden rumor ran round the farm that something
had happened to Boxer.
He had gone out alone to drag a load of stone down to the windmill,
and sure enough, the rumor was true.
A few minutes later, two pigeons came racing in with the news.
>> Boxer has fallen. He is lying on his side and can't get up.
>> About half the animals on the farm rushed out to the knoll where the windmill stood.
There lay Boxer between the shafts of the cart, his neck stretched out, unable
even to raise his head.
His eyes were glazed, his sides matted with sweat.
A thin stream of blood had trickled out of his mouth.
Clover drops to her knees at his side.
>> Boxer, how are you?
>> It is my lung.
It does not matter.
I think you will be able to finish the windmill without me.
There is a pretty good store of stone accumulated.
I had only another month to go in any case.
To tell you the truth, I had been looking forward to my retirement,
and perhaps, as Benjamin is growing old, too, they will let him retire at the
same time and be a companion to me.
>> We must get help at once. Run, somebody, and tell Squealer what has happened.
>> All the other animals immediately raced back to the farmhouse to give Squealer the news.
Only Clover remained, and Benjamin, who lay down at Boxer's side, and without
speaking, kept the flies off him with his long tail.
After about a quarter of an hour, Squealer appeared, full of sympathy and concern.
He said that Comrade Napoleon had learned with the very deepest distress
of this misfortune to one of the most loyal workers on the farm
and was already making arrangements to send Boxer to be treated in the hospital at Willingdon.
The animals felt a little uneasy at this.
Except for Mollie and Snowball, no other animal had ever left the farm
and they did not like to think of their sick comrade in the hands of human beings.
However, Squealer easily convinced them that the veterinary surgeon in
Willingdon could treat Boxer's case more satisfactorily than could be done on the farm.
And about half an hour later, when Boxer had somewhat recovered, he was, with
difficulty, got onto his feet and managed to limp back to his stall, where
Clover and Benjamin had prepared a good bed of straw for him.
For the next two days, Boxer remained in his stall. The pigs had sent out a large
bottle of pink medicine, which they had found in the medicine chest in the bathroom,
and Clover administered it to Boxer twice a day after meals.
In the evenings, she lay in his stall and talked to him, while Benjamin kept
the flies off him.
Boxer professed not to be sorry for what had happened.
If he made a good recovery, he might expect to live another three years and
he looked forward to the peaceful days that he would spend in the corner of the big pasture.
It would be the first time that he had had leisure to study and improve his mind.
He intended, he said, to devote the rest of his life to learning the remaining 22
letters of the alphabet.
However, Benjamin and Clover could only be with Boxer after working hours and it
was in the middle of the day when the van came to take him away.
The animals were all at work weeding turnips under the supervision of a pig
when they were astonished to see Benjamin come galloping from the